A Guide to the Loudoun County Military Records, Circa 1779-1861
Thomas Balch Library
Thomas Balch Library
Loudoun County Military Records ca. 1779-1861
Thomas Balch Library
M 015
.33 cu. ft.
The Loudoun County Military Records are extracts from rosters which list military personnel and officers enrolled in various units from the Revolutionary War to the year 1861.
Unknown
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection open for research
Acquisition Information
Unknown
Alternative Form Available
None
Accruals
2005.0096X, 2005.0097X
Historical Information
The Loudoun County Military Records are extracts from rosters which list military personnel and officers enrolled in various units from the Revolutionary War to the year 1861. The lists in this collection are both photocopied and handwritten.
Scope and Content
The first records are from the years 1779-1782, and may contain information such as soldiers' names, dates of enlistment, location in the government roster, date and location of death, and names of soldiers' wives and sons. Militia lists from the Revolutionary War are particularly concerned with soldiers from the Third, Fifth, and Seventh Virginia Regiments. The rosters from the War of 1812 include lists of members of the Thirty-Seventh, Forty-Fourth, Fifty-Fifth, Fifty-Sixth, Fifty-Seventh, Sixtieth, and Eighty-Ninth Regiments. These rolls may contain information concerning rank, commencement of service, expiration of service, place of residence, place of discharge, distance of place of discharge to place of residence, names present, and additional remarks. The concluding folders are regimental payrolls from the 1830s through the year 1861. These rosters list name, rank, commencement of service/settlement, ending of pay, time paid for, amount of pay, subsistence, retained bounty, total amount [of pay], and additional remarks.
The Loudoun County militia lists are the only items in this collection.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Other Finding Aid
None
Related Material
None
Contents List
- (Box 1)
  - Militia Lists - Revolutionary War, 1779-1782
  - List of Recruits - Revolutionary War, 1780
  - 3rd Virginia Payroll, Revolutionary War, 1777
  - 5th Virginia Payroll, Revolutionary War, 1776
  - 3rd and 7th Virginia Muster Rolls, Revolutionary War, 1777
  - Loudoun Co., VA Soldiers - Revolutionary War, ca. 1779-1783
  - Loudoun Co. Count Orders/Militia Lists/Continental Army Appts. - Revolutionary War, ca. 1779-1783
  - 36th Regiment Muster Roll, ca. 1812-1815
  - 44th Regiment List of Officers and Soldiers, ca. 1812-1815
  - 55th Regiment, Jefferson Co., VA, ca. 1812-1815
  - 56th Regiment, ca. 1812-1815
  - Loudoun Co. 57th Regiment Payroll, ca. 1812-1815
  - 60th Regiment Muster Roll, ca. 1812-1815
  - 89th Regiment Payroll, ca. 1812-1815
  - Loudoun Co. Militia Muster Rolls, ca. 1812-1815
  - Disbursements and Muster Rolls, ca. 1812-1815
  - VA Army Units, ca. 1812-1815
  - Militia Records, 2nd Battalion: Purcellville, Lovettsville, Hillsboro, 1830-1840s
  - Loudoun Co. Property Taxes and Disbursements, 1830-1853
  - Loudoun Co. 56th Regiment Meetings, 1842-1860
  - 56th Regiment, 1st and 2nd Battalions, 1845-1858
  - Battalion and Regiment lists, 1858-1861